# **Julian Beard**

### Full-Stack Software Engineer

(517) 626-4000 · julian.beard93@gmail.com · julianbeard.codes · jn/julian-a-beard · github.com/badjab326

Southern California based Full-Stack Software Engineer with experience in various team-based agile software development projects, and an extensive repertoire of communication, team building and resource management skills.

## **SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python | Libraries and Frameworks - Angular, React, Node.js, Express.js, Django Database - MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose | Other - Angular Material, ChakraUl, REST, Tailwind CSS, Postman

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Idoona, Full-Stack Software Engineer | Remote

Sep. 2022 - Present

- Plan architecture for new software projects, determining appropriate tech stack and MVP outline.
- Collaborate with cross-functional team members in an agile workspace to ensure high-quality output.
- Build and maintain client-scale applications using MERN stack (Mongo, Express, React, Node) and Payload CMS.
- Conduct research and present demos to leadership of new frameworks for integration.
- Develop a user-centric sustainability tool leveraging Government data for enhanced functionality.

### Dreamcatch Development, Full-Stack Software Engineer (Contract) | Remote

April 2023 - Present

- Engineer a variety of applications to client technology and product requirements in a fast-paced environment.
- Meet directly with clients to demo latest builds, itemize feedback into actionable items, and map out project timelines.
- Develop Nest.js backends and MySQL databases in version-controlled environments for optimal performance and scalability.
- Design responsive interfaces using flexbox, media queries, and Tailwind CSS, enabling consistency across devices.
- Use strong communication and team management skills to work with diverse clients and ensure successful project outcomes.

#### Alaska Airlines, Flight Attendant | Los Angeles, CA

Oct. 2017 - May 2022

- Demonstrated exceptional time management skills, ensuring optimal and safe service delivery under tight time constraints.
- Used strong communication and team management skills to effectively work with diverse groups of individuals.
- Adapted flexibly to constant changes within the industry and individual flights, demonstrating patience and resilience.
- Consistently learned and incorporated new skills and safety procedures into my workflow as needed.
- Exercised utmost care and confidentiality in handling secure information.

# **LIVE PROJECTS**

### Gliddy

- Engineered to client's 'Mobile First' Figma design specifications using React, Tailwind CSS and Chakra UI.
- Made use of Node.js, Nest.js, and MySql to manage backend operations, live database updates and Twilio integration.
- Provided direct client support and requested feature updates through the end of development timeline.

### **Black In Gaming**

- Built from the ground up using Angular, TypeScript, Angular Material, Node and PayloadCMS.
- Utilizes Node.js backend and PayloadCMS to manage and serve detailed information on Black video game characters.
- Custom components built using Angular Material and designed with mobile browsers in mind via responsive design.

## **Gym Planner**

- Produced app designed to give users the ability to digitally plan, track and optimize their workouts.
- Constructed with Python, Django, Materialize CSS and PostgreSQL.
- Implemented full user authentication and authorization, as well as admin functionality.

# **EDUCATION**

### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE**

2022

Software Engineering Immersive

Completed an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies, including development of multiple individual and group projects.

COURSERA | REMOTE 2022

Meta Full-Stack Engineering

Certified in multiple Software Engineering courses offered and sponsored by Meta:

- Introduction to Front-End Development
- HTML and CSS in depth
- Programming with JavaScript
- React Basics

- Introduction to Back-End Development
- Version Control
- Programming in Python